<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TensorTales</title>
    <link>https://markkurzeja.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TensorTales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://markkurzeja.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Orthonormal Matrices For Deep Learning Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://markkurzeja.github.io/post/orthonormal_recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markkurzeja.github.io/post/orthonormal_recipe/</guid>
      <description>Prelude I have been researching alternative methods to initialize and parameterize dense layers for use in deep learning pipelines. Orthonormal matrices have several interesting properties, including fast inverses (via their transpose) and unit eigenvalues which make them interesting candidates for several methods.&#xA;When coding up solutions, however, the naive QR decomposition proved to be far too slow and cumbersome for generating these matrices. So I turned to the Matrix Cookbook and &amp;ldquo;got cooking&amp;rdquo; looking for alternative methods of parametrization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random Fourier Features, Part I </title>
      <link>https://markkurzeja.github.io/post/rff_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markkurzeja.github.io/post/rff_intro/</guid>
      <description>Random Fourier Features (RFF), in my opinion, have one of the best performance-to-cost tradeoffs in machine learning techniques today. Simple to code, cheap to fit, and unreasonably effective, they have been my bread-and-butter for small-to-medium multi-dimensional learning tasks and serve as an decent baseline for more complex systems.&#xA;This post will be the first of a three part series on RFF:&#xA;Post I: This post will help to build intuition of RFF through low-dimensional examples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://markkurzeja.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markkurzeja.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Senior Software Engineer at Google. My current focus is on using machine learning to combat malware on Android devices. I have my BBA from the Ross School of Business at the University of Michigan and a Masters in Statistics from the Racknam Graduate School at the University of Michigan. My research interests are in machine learning generally, including deep learning, business, and statistics.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
